smarta.com 2018-08-18

# - Business Builder

Version: 1.0  Date: 24/05/2018 

### Privacy Statement Summary:

|   
---|---  
  
Who will use my data? 

| 

Smarta Enterprises Ltd   
  
What for? 

| 

We will store and process your data in order to allow us to provide our products and services to you. We may also send you offer details that we think you will be interested in. This may include a range of our related products and services. We may also use your data to process financial products and services. We will only process your data in relation to financial service with your explicit consent.   
  
What will happen if I contact you? 

| 

If you contact us we will use your information, send you the information you have requested and updates, offers and other information that we think you will be interested in.   
  
What data will be stored? 

| 

We will store your personal details in order to provide our services to you. We will store details of purchase enquiries, purchases, and related financial information as required. 

All data entered into our third party services, are there responsibility, and they will have updated Privacy Policies and Terms and Conditions in line with GDPR 2018.   
  
What data will be shared? 

| 

We will share your data with our third party partners included in Smarta Business Builder who will receive your Account registration details. 

We will share your information with any regulator or legal body that requests it.   
  
How long? 

| 

Your data will be stored only for  7 years  after which time your data will be deleted.   
  
Who can access my data? 

| 

We will never sell, share or otherwise distribute your data to any other third party.   
  
How is my data kept secure? 

| 

We will store your data on secure UK based servers which will be processed in the UK. We use industry standard security protocols/technology to secure data.   
  
We take your privacy seriously and will only use your personal information to provide the products and services you have requested from us and to send you information about products and services you may be interested in. We will never sell, share or use your personal information other than as described here. 

### About This Privacy Policy

This policy sets out how we will use and share the information that you give us. This policy describes your relationship with Smarta Enterprises Ltd. 

The Data Protection Act 1998 (DPA) and General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) describes how organisations must collect, handle, process and store personal information. 

These rules apply regardless of whether data is stored electronically, on paper or on other materials.  
To comply with the law, personal information must be collected and used fairly, stored safely and not disclosed unlawfully. GDPR is underpinned by eight important principals. These say that personal data must: 

  1. Be processed fairly and lawfully 
  2. Be obtained only for specific, lawful purposes 
  3. Be adequate, relevant and not excessive 
  4. Be accurate and kept up to date 
  5. Not be held for any longer than is necessary 
  6. Processed in accordance with the rights of the data subjects 
  7. Be protected in appropriate ways 
  8. Not be transferred outside the European Economic Area, unless that country or territory also ensures an adequate level of protection. 

We take these responsibilities seriously, this document describes our approach to data protection. 

This policy helps to protect us from data security risks, including: 

  * Breaches of confidentiality. For instance, information being given out inappropriately. 
  * Failing to offer choice. For instance, all individuals should be free to choose how the company uses data relating to them. 
  * Reputational damage. For instance, the company could suffer if hackers successfully gained access to sensitive data. 

### Who we are and how to contact us

Smarta is a trading name of Smarta Enterprises Ltd is registered in England and Wales and is registered with the Information Commissioner's Office under the Data Protection Act 1998. The data controller is: Smarta Enterprises Ltd. You can contact us in any of the following ways 

Email: privacy@smarta.com  
Phone: +44 (0) 330 335 1570  Website: www.smarta.com  Post: No.1 Croydon, 7th Floor, 12-16 Addiscombe Road, Croydon, CR0 0XT 

### Who this privacy policy applies to

Smarta Enterprises Ltd is a provider of information, cloud-based software and tools to help start-ups and SMEs to start, manage and grow their business. This policy relates to users of Smarta Enterprises Ltd. Processing of your data is required in order to offer you these services. This policy applies to    individuals who have shared their data with Smarta Enterprises Ltd as either a customer, employee, supplier or in any other capacity. 

It applies to all data that the company holds relating to identifiable individuals, even if that information technically falls outside of the DPA and GDPR. This can include: 

  * \- Name, address, email, telephone number, username and password (collectively "Account Information") 
  * \- Credit card, debit card, banking or other payment information 
  * \- Information submitted as a result of completing forms on our Websites or Portals, entering a promotion or survey or subscribing to, commenting on or downloading information from our Websites or Portals. 
  * \- Technical information as a result of configuring the Products and Services, including IP addresses, browser-type, device-type, internet service provider, referring or exiting pages, operating system, date and time stamp or clickstream data 
  * \- Any other information shared with us directly or indirectly through a customer's or user's use of the Products and Services, Websites or Portals 

### What this policy applies to

This section describes the lawful basis for processing your data and applies to the information about yourself that you choose to provide us with or that you allow us to collect. This includes: 

  * \- Information you contact us and request information such as your name, email address and contact details, and other preferences 
  * \- When you contact us in order to discuss using our services 
  * \- Information we collect about how you use the website 
  * \- Information relating to products and services we offer to you and other transactions including financial and other personal information required to complete these transactions 
  * \- Information given and stored as part of our ongoing relationship 
  * \- We do not collect or process sensitive data about you. 

### How your information will be used

We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it and as you would reasonably expect your data to be processed and only where there is a lawful basis for such processing, for example: 

Purpose/Activity 

| 

Type of data 

| 

Lawful basis for processing   
  
---|---|---  
  
To register you as a new customer 

| 

(a) Identity, (b) Contact 

| 

Performance of a contract with you   
  
To process and deliver the products and services you request including managing payments, fees and charges, and to collect and recover money owed to us 

| 

(a) Identity, (b) Contact, (c) Financial, (d) Transaction, (e) Marketing and Communications 

| 

(a) Performance of a contract with you, (b) Necessary for our legitimate interests to recover debts owed to us   
  
To manage our ongoing relationship with you which will include notifying you about changes to our terms, products and services, or privacy policy, to maintain our records 

| 

(a) Identity, (b) Contact, (c) Profile, (d) Marketing and Communications 

| 

(a) Performance of a contract with you, (b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation, (c) Necessary for our legitimate interests to keep our records updated and to study how customers use our products/services   
  
To administer and protect our business and our site (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data) 

| 

(a) Identity, (b) Contact, (c) Technical 

| 

(a) Necessary for our legitimate interests for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganisation or group restructuring exercise, (b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation   
  
To deliver relevant content and advertisements to you and measure and understand the effectiveness of our advertising 

| 

(a) Identity, (b) Contact, (c) Profile, (d) Usage, (e) Marketing and Communications, (f) Technical 

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them, to grow our business and to inform our marketing strategy   
  
To use data analytics to improve our website, products/services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences 

| 

(a) Technical, (b) Usage 

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests to define types of customers for our products and services, to keep our site updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy   
  
To make suggestions and recommendations to you about goods or services that may be of interest to you 

| 

(a) Identity, (b) Contact, (c) Technical, (d) Usage, (e) Profile 

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests to develop our products/services and grow our business   
  
We will collect and process information about you, including your name, date of birth, address, contact details (including email address and mobile phone number), product and service details, purchase history and data collected as part of any finance application or payment (including previous addresses, employment details and bank account details). 

We will take personal information from: 

  * \- Information that you provide to us when registering with our website (including your email address); 
  * \- Information that you provide when completing your online profile (including your name, gender, date of birth and company name, address and main activity); 
  * \- Information that you provide to us when signing up to any distribution lists to receive correspondence from us; 
  * \- Information relating to any purchases you make of our goods or services, including any other transaction details made via any of our websites (including your address, telephone number and payment details) 

Personal data we receive will be used for the purposes it was provided, including: 

  * \- To respond to queries from you regarding the possible purchase of goods or services; 
  * \- To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us including provision of services, and to respond to queries from you regarding those contracts; 
  * \- To manage and administer the relationships between you and us; 
  * \- To notify you about changes to our services and to otherwise communicate with you; for example, we will use your contact details in order to respond to any queries that you submit to us; and 
  * \- To obtain feedback from you regarding us. 

In accordance with your preferences, we may also use your personal information to provide you with information about products, services, promotions and offers that may be of interest to you. We may use your personal information in order to ascertain the services, promotions and offers that are likely to be of particular interest to you. This document explains how you can change whether to receive this information. Please note that, even if you choose not to receive this information, we may still use your personal information to provide you with important services communications, including communications in relation to any purchases you make or services you use. 

### How to change your preferences

We operate in line with EU GDPR (May 2018) data protection guidelines. We respect your rights and will respond to any request for access to personal information and requests to delete, rectify, transfer, data and to stop processing. We will also advise you on how to complain to the relevant authorities, namely the Information Commissioner’s Office. Any requests or objections should be made in writing to the Data Controller or you can visit our website, call, or email us to contact us to change your preferences at anytime. 

### Scope of Agreement

By submitting your personal data on this site or as required for us to provide products and services to you, you are affirming your agreement for such information to be used in accordance with this privacy policy. You will be able to change your preferences at any time by the methods described as prescribed in this document. 

We may from time to time use your information for marketing, account management or relationship management purposes. The main purpose of this is to provide you with information about goods and services which we think may be of interest to you and/or to maintain any existing relationship we may have with you. 

### Opting out at a later date

Where you give your consent for us to process your data, for example when you agree to us sending you marketing information or where you agree to us processing financial data, you can contact us to amend or withdraw your consent at anytime. You can also choose to object to processing and request deletion of your data. We respect all user rights as defined in GDPR. If you have any comments or wish to complain please contact us. 

### How we store and process your data

Your data will be collected stored and processed in the UK only, we do not transfer your data outside the EU. Your data will be stored for up to 7 years to ensure we have records of service, payments, and other interactions we have with you. 

In order to provide or services to you we use recognised third parties to take payment, conduct credit reports and other checks, manage our company accounts and provide banking services. We will store transactions, payment and order data for up to 7 years or for as long as required by UK financial and company regulations. These third parties may operate outside the EU, if this is the case we will ensure precautions are in place to protect your data. 

We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to find out more about how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please email us. If we need to use your personal data for a purpose unrelated to the purpose for which we collected the data, we will notify you and we will explain the legal ground of processing. 

We may be legally obliged to disclose your personal information without your knowledge to the extent that we are required to do so by law; in connection with any ongoing or prospective legal proceedings; in order to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights (including providing information to others for the purposes of fraud prevention and reducing credit risk); to any person who we reasonably believe may apply to a court or other competent authority for disclosure of that personal information where, in our reasonable opinion, such court or authority would be reasonably likely to order disclosure of that personal information]. 

You will only receive marketing communications from us if you have: 

  * \- requested information from us or purchased goods or services from us; or 
  * \- if you provided us with your details and ticked the box at the point of entry of your details for us to send you marketing communications; and 
  * \- in each case, you have not opted out of receiving that marketing. 

We will get your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any third party for marketing purposes. 

### Our obligations

**We are a data controller**. In relation to the information that you provide to us, we are legally responsible for how that information is handled. We will comply with the Data Protection Act 1998 and the GDPR (2018) in the way we use and share your personal data. 

Among other things, this means that we will only use your personal data:

  * \- Fairly and lawfully 
  * \- As set out in the legislation and this policy 
  * \- To the extent necessary for these purposes 
  * \- We will take steps to ensure your data is accurate and rectify data as necessary 

Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data.

These include the right to:

  * \- Request access to your personal data. 
  * \- Request correction of your personal data. 
  * \- Request erasure of your personal data. 
  * \- Object to processing of your personal data. 
  * \- Request restriction of processing your personal data. 
  * \- Request transfer of your personal data. 
  * \- Right to withdraw consent. 

You can see more about these rights at:  [ https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/individual-rights/](https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/individual-rights/)

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances. 

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response. 

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated. 

### Third Parties

We will share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes described in this document: 

  * \- Service providers who provide IT and system administration services. 
  * \- Professional advisers including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers who provide consultancy, credit scoring, banking, legal, fraud protection, insurance and accounting services. 
  * \- HM Revenue & Customs, regulators and other authorities based in the United Kingdom and other relevant jurisdictions who require reporting of processing activities in certain circumstances. 
  * \- Third parties to whom we sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets. 
  * \- Smarta Enterprises Ltd have a contractual agreement with the following third party providers of Smarta Business Builder, your data is only passed onto them once you have signed up to trial or pay for their services:  Partner | Description of service | Based inside UK | GDPR Compliant/ or equivalent  
---|---|---|---  
  
BaseKit

| 

Website builder

| 

Yes

| 

Yes  
  
Company Check

| 

Access to company credit reports across Europe

|  |   
  
FreeAgent

| 

Accountancy software

| 

Yes

| 

Yes  
  
Fusemail

| 

Professional email hosting solution

| 

No

| 

Yes  
  
LivePlan

| 

Business Plan templates

| 

No

| 

Yes (Privacy Shield)  
  
Law Assure

| 

Legal document template generator

| 

Yes

| 

Yes  
  
Mozy

| 

Cloud data protection

| 

No

| 

Yes (Privacy Shield)  
  
Sage One

| 

Accountancy software

| 

Yes

| 

Yes  

We require all third parties to whom we transfer your data to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We only allow such third parties to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions. 

### Security

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know such data. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality. 

We will report any breaches or potential breaches to the appropriate authorities within 24 hours and to anyone affected by a breach within 72 hours. If you have any queries or concerns about your data usage, please contact us. 

This website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit. 

### Legitimate Interests

Under the Data Protection Act, we are also permitted to share some information with third parties who use such data for non-marketing purposes (including credit and risk assessment and management, identification and fraud prevention, debt collection and returning assets to you). 

### Contacting us, exercising your information rights and Complaints

If you any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, wish to exercise your information rights in connection with the personal data you have shared with us or wish to complain, please contact: The Data Protection Officer at Smarta Enterprises Ltd. 

We will process SARs within 20 days, SAR responses are usually free but we reserve the right to charge for excessive or unfounded requests. We fully comply with Data Protection legislation and will assist in any investigation or request made by the appropriate authorities. 

If you remain dissatisfied then you have the right to apply directly to the Information Commissioner for a decision. 

The Information Commissioner can be contacted at: 

Information Commissioner’s Office  
Wycliffe House  
Water Lane  
Wilmslow  
Cheshire  
SK9 5AF  www.ico.org.uk  
Wycliffe House
